questions=[
	{
		question:"1. Which group supported American independence?",
		wAnswer:"Tories",
		rAnswer:"Whigs"
	},
  {
    question:"2. Who said: \"Give me liberty or give me death!\"?",
    wAnswer:"Paul Revere",
    rAnswer:"Patrick Henry"
  },
  {
    question:"3. Who was the Commander in Chief of the Continental Army?",
    wAnswer:"Thomas Jefferson",
    rAnswer:"George Washington"
  },
  {
    question:"4. What was the call for peace written to King George called?",
    wAnswer:"Apple Tree Petition",
    rAnswer:"Olive Branch Petition"
  },
  {
    question:"5. Who wrote the pamphlet: \"Common Sense\"?",
    wAnswer:"Ben Franklin",
    rAnswer:"Thomas Paine"
  },
  {
    question:"6. Who was the American ambassador to France?",
    wAnswer:"Thomas Jefferson",
    rAnswer:"Ben Franklin"
  },
  {
    question:"7. What was the treaty that ended the Revolutionary War?",
    wAnswer:"Treaty of Versailles",
    rAnswer:"Treaty of Paris"
  },
  {
    question:"8. Which country aided America in the war?",
    wAnswer:"Spain",
    rAnswer:"France"
  },
  {
    question:"9. Who was defeated at the Battle of Yorktown?",
    wAnswer:"Robert E. Lee",
    rAnswer:"Charles Cornwallis"
  },
  {
    question:"10. What was significant about the date of the Battle of Trenton?",
    wAnswer:"Fourth of July",
    rAnswer:"Christmas Day"
  },
  {
    question:"11. Who did George III hire to fight the Americans?",
    wAnswer:"The Prussians",
    rAnswer:"The Hessians"
  },
  {
    question:"12. What battle was the \"turning point\" of the war?",
    wAnswer:"Battle of Bunker Hill",
    rAnswer:"Battle of Saratoga"
  },
  {
    question:"13. What cultural movement directly inspired the Revolution?",
    wAnswer:"The Renaissance",
    rAnswer:"The Enlightenment"
  },
  {
    question:"14. What was Nathan Hale's profession?",
    wAnswer:"a Pastor",
    rAnswer:"a Teacher"
  },
  {
    question:"15. What faction did the majority of colonists align with?",
    wAnswer:"Loyalists",
    rAnswer:"Patriots"
  },
  {
    question: "16. Who made the infamous \"Midnight Ride\"?",
    wAnswer:"Paul Revere",
    rAnswer:"Sam Prescott"
  }
]